<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sam E. Cutler</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://samecutler.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Sam E. Cutler</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024 Sam Cutler</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://samecutler.github.io/media/icon_hue11b335ae175fd4abb2262113e3113ef_438264_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Sam E. Cutler</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/</link></image><item><title>The UNCOVER Survey: A First-look HST + JWST Catalog of 60,000 Galaxies near A2744 and beyond</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/weaver-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/weaver-2024/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The UNCOVER Survey: A First-look HST+JWST Catalog of Galaxy Redshifts and Stellar Population Properties Spanning 0.2 ensuremathłesssim z ensuremathłesssim 15</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/wang-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/wang-2024/</guid><description/></item><item><title>JWST UNCOVER: The Overabundance of Ultraviolet-luminous Galaxies at $z>9$</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/chemerynska-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/chemerynska-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Two Distinct Classes of Quiescent Galaxies at Cosmic Noon Revealed by JWST PRIMER and UNCOVER</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/jwstsizes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/jwstsizes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Remarkably Compact Quiescent Candidates at 3&lt;z&lt;5 in JWST-CEERS</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/wright-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/wright-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Heavy Metal Survey: Star Formation Constraints and Dynamical Masses of 21 Massive Quiescent Galaxies at zåisebox-0.5ex~1.4-2.2</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/kriek-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/kriek-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UNCOVER: A NIRSpec Identification of a Broad-line AGN at z = 8.50</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/kokorev-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/kokorev-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quantifying the Effects of Known Unknowns on Inferred High-redshift Galaxy Properties: Burstiness, the IMF, and Nebular Physics</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/wang-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/wang-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UNCOVER: The rest ultraviolet to near infrared multiwavelength structures and dust distributions of sub-millimeter-detected galaxies in Abell 2744</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/price-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/price-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>astrowhit/aperpy: v1.0.1</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/weaver-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/weaver-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dust attenuation, dust content, and geometry of star-forming galaxies</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/zhang-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/zhang-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UNCOVER spectroscopy confirms a surprising ubiquity of AGN in red galaxies at $z>5$</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/greene-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/greene-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UNCOVER: The Growth of the First Massive Black Holes from JWST/NIRSpec-Spectroscopic Redshift Confirmation of an X-Ray Luminous AGN at z = 10.1</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/goulding-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/goulding-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A supermassive black hole in the early universe growing in the shadows</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/furtak-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/furtak-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>First spectroscopic observations of the galaxies that reionized the Universe</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/atek-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/atek-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rapid Quenching of Galaxies at Cosmic Noon</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/park-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/park-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UNCOVER: A NIRSpec Census of Lensed Galaxies at z=8.50-13.08 Probing a High AGN Fraction and Ionized Bubbles in the Shadow</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/fujimoto-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/fujimoto-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UNCOVER: JWST Spectroscopy of Three Cold Brown Dwarfs at Kiloparsec-scale Distances</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/burgasser-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/burgasser-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>UNCOVER: Candidate Red Active Galactic Nuclei at 3&lt;z&lt;7 with JWST and ALMA</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/labbe-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/labbe-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Measuring Star-Formation Histories at z 2 with a Semi-Resolved Approach</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/cutler-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/cutler-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The JWST UNCOVER Treasury survey: Ultradeep NIRSpec and NIRCam ObserVations before the Epoch of Reionization</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/bezanson-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/bezanson-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>3D-DASH</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/3ddash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:51:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/3ddash/</guid><description>&lt;p>3D-DASH is the follow-up program to COSMOS-DASH, extending the total area to 1.43 sq. deg. in HST WFC3/F160W, making it the largest survey done by HST in the near-IR. 3D-DASH imaging and related tools are available on the &lt;a href="https://archive.stsci.edu/hlsp/3d-dash" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3D-DASH MAST page&lt;/a>. In the next few months we will be creating a deep, multi-band HST-selected 3D-DASH photometric catalog utilizing all HST data in the entire COSMOS field, via the &lt;a href="https://github.com/astrowhit/aperpy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>aperpy&lt;/em> code&lt;/a>. 3D-DASH imaging will also be utilized in a project to measure color gradients in z~2 quiescent galaxies, which then will help infer the overall shape of the star-formation histories of these quenched galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HLF GOODS-N Photometric Catalog</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/hlfgoodsn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:51:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/hlfgoodsn/</guid><description>&lt;p>Using the &lt;em>aperpy&lt;/em> code (in development) we are building a robust photometric catalog from &lt;a href="https://archive.stsci.edu/prepds/hlf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hubble Legacy Field&lt;/a> GOODS-N imaging. The catalog will contain psf-matched aperture photometry from 11 HST bands from the UV to near-IR. Detailed information on the catalog creation process can be found for the &lt;a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.3847/1538-4365/ab3853/pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HLF GOODS-S Photometric Catalog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Differential Assembly History of the Centers and Outskirts of Main Sequence Galaxies at $z∼2.3$</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/insideout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/insideout/</guid><description/></item><item><title>3D-DASH: The Widest Near-infrared Hubble Space Telescope Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/mowla-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/mowla-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Diagnosing DASH: A Catalog of Structural Properties for the COSMOS-DASH Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/cutler-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/cutler-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Diagnosing DASH: A Catalog of Structural Properties for the COSMOS-DASH Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/dash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/dash/</guid><description/></item><item><title>COSMOS-DASH</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/cosmos-dash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:51:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/cosmos-dash/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hubble Space Telescope (HST) resolution is crucial in measuring the structural properties of high-redshift or blended galaxies. However, large area surveys are traditionally observationally expensive to obtain with HST, especially in the near-infrared. The COSMOS-DASH survey utilizes the novel &amp;ldquo;Drift And SHift&amp;rdquo; (DASH) technique to efficiently observe up to eight pointings in a single orbit using HST. This is done by guiding with gyros alone (i.e. diabling fine guidance sensors after the first pointing), which allows for wide-area surveys in the NIR with HST resolution, including the 0.49 square degree COSMOS-DASH survey. I lead the creation of the COSMOS-DASH morphological catalog, which provides structural parameters for over 50,000 galaxies with an increased number of massive galaxies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The COSMOS-DASH mosaics and morphological catalog, along with a more detailed description of the program are available on the &lt;a href="https://archive.stsci.edu/hlsp/cosmos-dash" target="_blank" rel="noopener">COSMOS-DASH MAST page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resolved SED fitting with Prospector</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/resolved-prospector/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:51:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/resolved-prospector/</guid><description>&lt;p>The formation of the central parts of &amp;ldquo;typical&amp;rdquo; star-forming galaxies is an open question in astronomy. To investigate this, we present a sample of 60 z~2.3 main-sequence galaxies from the &lt;a href="http://mosdef.astro.berkeley.edu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MOSFIRE Deep Evolution Field (MOSDEF)&lt;/a> spectroscopic survey. Using the &lt;a href="https://prospect.readthedocs.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prospector code&lt;/a> with strong metallicity priors from MOSDEF spectra, we fit SEDs to resolved central and outer components, using a novel iterative method to robustly incorporate unresolved &lt;em>Spitzer&lt;/em>/IRAC and &lt;em>K&lt;/em>-band data. This technique allows us to get well-constrained, non-parametric star formation histories for the central and outer regions of these typical main-sequence galaxies (see the figure above), which provides insight into the overall assembly of star-forming galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Differential Assembly of the Centers and Outskirts of Main Sequence Galaxies at z~2.3</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/the-differential-assembly-of-the-centers-and-outskirts-of-main-sequence-galaxies-at-z~2.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/the-differential-assembly-of-the-centers-and-outskirts-of-main-sequence-galaxies-at-z~2.3/</guid><description>&lt;p>We present a sample of 60 z~2.3 main sequence, star-forming galaxies from the MOSDEF survey in GOODS-N with SED fits to decomposed central and outer components. These galaxies are decomposed into two components using apertures selected from observed z-H colors. SED fitting is done with Prospector on HST ACS and WFC3, &lt;em>Spitzer&lt;/em>/IRAC, and ground-based photometry, with additional constraints from MOSDEF metallicities and spectroscopic redshifts. Because we decompose the galaxies into only two components, we are able to iteratively determine the IRAC and ground-based photometry of each component while conserving total flux. Our final sample contains stellar population parameters and SFHs for the center, outskirts, and integrated light of each galaxy. SFHs indicate that the majority of galaxies with logM&amp;lt;10.5 form their central region in bursts of star formation. Moreover, the galaxies with the sharpest peaks in SFR span a wide range in size and central density. This implies that the formation of these central parts likely occurred via an increase in the accretion rate of star forming clumps, rather than the collapse of a gaseous disk. Further analysis of the uncertainties from the decomposition and choice of priors is necessary to determine if these results are robust.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diagnosing DASH: A Morphological Catalog for the COSMOS-DASH Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/diagnosing-dash-a-morphological-catalog-for-the-cosmos-dash-survey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/diagnosing-dash-a-morphological-catalog-for-the-cosmos-dash-survey/</guid><description>&lt;p>COSMOS-DASH is a 0.5 square degree survey of the COSMOS field, obtained utilizing the novel “Drift And SHift” (DASH) observing technique for HST-WFC3 imaging. While DASH observations are significantly more efficient than standard HST imaging, they also are shallower and have an unusual data reduction, both of which may impact morphology measurements for fainter galaxies. In this talk I will present the F160W morphological catalog for for 51,534 galaxies in the COSMOS-DASH survey. Using morphological measurements from GALFIT, we recover consistent results with those from the deeper 3D-HST morphological catalogs out to z=2 and logM~10. I will also discuss the parameter space where morphological fits of DASH galaxies are robustly recovered. At logM&amp;lt;10.5, we find a flattening of the quiescent size-mass relation, implying the sizes of low mass quiescent galaxies are more similar to star-forming galaxies with a similar redshift and mass. Trends with axis-ratio and environment also suggest that low mass galaxies that quench in low density environments may retain morphologies comparable to similar mass star-forming galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diagnosing DASH: A Morphological Catalog for the COSMOS-DASH Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/cutler-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/cutler-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Examining High Redshift Rotation Curves and Dark Matter Profiles Outside the Local Universe</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/cutler-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/cutler-2018/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://samecutler.github.io/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item><item><title>PRIMER</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/primer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/primer/</guid><description>&lt;p>The JWST &lt;a href="https://primer-jwst.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PRIMER&lt;/a> Treasury survey is a&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Quiescent Galaxy Sizes with JWST</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/jwst-sizes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/jwst-sizes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Several previous HST-based studies (including &lt;a href="https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2022ApJ...925...34C/abstract" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cutler et al. 2022&lt;/a>) have found a flattening of sizes at the low-mass end of the quiescent size-mass relation. Using the improved sensitivity and spatial resolution, and redder wavelength coverage of JWST/NIRCam, we investigate the sizes of low-mass quiescent galaxies in the &lt;a href="https://primer-jwst.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PRIMER&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://jwst-uncover.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UNCOVER&lt;/a> Treasury surveys at cosmic noon (1&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;3). A sample of 332 7&amp;lt;logM&amp;lt;11 galaxies are selected using &lt;em>UVJ&lt;/em> and sSFR criteria and modeled in both F150W and F444W using (&lt;em>GALFIT&lt;/em>)[https://users.obs.carnegiescience.edu/peng/work/galfit/galfit.html]. With these measurements, we find the properties of low-mass quiescent galaxies differ dramatically from their massive counterparts and are better classified as an entirely separate population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UNCOVER</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/uncover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/uncover/</guid><description>&lt;p>The JWST &lt;a href="https://jwst-uncover.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UNCOVER&lt;/a> Treasury survey is a&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>