<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks | Sam E. Cutler</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/event/</link><atom:link href="https://samecutler.github.io/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024 Sam Cutler</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://samecutler.github.io/media/icon_hue11b335ae175fd4abb2262113e3113ef_438264_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/event/</link></image><item><title>The Differential Assembly of the Centers and Outskirts of Main Sequence Galaxies at z~2.3</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/the-differential-assembly-of-the-centers-and-outskirts-of-main-sequence-galaxies-at-z~2.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/the-differential-assembly-of-the-centers-and-outskirts-of-main-sequence-galaxies-at-z~2.3/</guid><description>&lt;p>We present a sample of 60 z~2.3 main sequence, star-forming galaxies from the MOSDEF survey in GOODS-N with SED fits to decomposed central and outer components. These galaxies are decomposed into two components using apertures selected from observed z-H colors. SED fitting is done with Prospector on HST ACS and WFC3, &lt;em>Spitzer&lt;/em>/IRAC, and ground-based photometry, with additional constraints from MOSDEF metallicities and spectroscopic redshifts. Because we decompose the galaxies into only two components, we are able to iteratively determine the IRAC and ground-based photometry of each component while conserving total flux. Our final sample contains stellar population parameters and SFHs for the center, outskirts, and integrated light of each galaxy. SFHs indicate that the majority of galaxies with logM&amp;lt;10.5 form their central region in bursts of star formation. Moreover, the galaxies with the sharpest peaks in SFR span a wide range in size and central density. This implies that the formation of these central parts likely occurred via an increase in the accretion rate of star forming clumps, rather than the collapse of a gaseous disk. Further analysis of the uncertainties from the decomposition and choice of priors is necessary to determine if these results are robust.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diagnosing DASH: A Morphological Catalog for the COSMOS-DASH Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/diagnosing-dash-a-morphological-catalog-for-the-cosmos-dash-survey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/diagnosing-dash-a-morphological-catalog-for-the-cosmos-dash-survey/</guid><description>&lt;p>COSMOS-DASH is a 0.5 square degree survey of the COSMOS field, obtained utilizing the novel “Drift And SHift” (DASH) observing technique for HST-WFC3 imaging. While DASH observations are significantly more efficient than standard HST imaging, they also are shallower and have an unusual data reduction, both of which may impact morphology measurements for fainter galaxies. In this talk I will present the F160W morphological catalog for for 51,534 galaxies in the COSMOS-DASH survey. Using morphological measurements from GALFIT, we recover consistent results with those from the deeper 3D-HST morphological catalogs out to z=2 and logM~10. I will also discuss the parameter space where morphological fits of DASH galaxies are robustly recovered. At logM&amp;lt;10.5, we find a flattening of the quiescent size-mass relation, implying the sizes of low mass quiescent galaxies are more similar to star-forming galaxies with a similar redshift and mass. Trends with axis-ratio and environment also suggest that low mass galaxies that quench in low density environments may retain morphologies comparable to similar mass star-forming galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>