<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks | Sam E. Cutler</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/event/</link><atom:link href="https://samecutler.github.io/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024 Sam Cutler</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://samecutler.github.io/media/icon_hue11b335ae175fd4abb2262113e3113ef_438264_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/event/</link></image><item><title>Low-Mass Quiescent Galaxy Sizes in the JWST PRIMER and UNCOVER Treasury Programs</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/low-mass-quiescent-galaxy-sizes-in-the-jwst-primer-and-uncover-treasury-programs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/low-mass-quiescent-galaxy-sizes-in-the-jwst-primer-and-uncover-treasury-programs/</guid><description>&lt;p>We present a sample of low-mass quiescent galaxy sizes measured from the JWST PRIMER and UNCOVER treasury surveys using NIRCam imaging. A conservative sample of robust low-mass quiescent galaxy candidates is selected using rest-frame UVJ colors and specific star formation rate selections. We examine galaxies in both F150W and F444W, as F150W provides higher spatial resolution while F444W observes wavelengths that better trace the stellar mass. Sizes are fit in both bands using 2D-Sérsic modeling with GALFIT. With the impressive spatial resolution afforded by JWST, we confirm an unambiguous flattening of the quiescent size-mass relation in both filters at the low-mass end. These low-mass quenched galaxies have more disk-like morphologies compared to the high Sérsic indices measured in their high-mass counterparts. The flattening, as well as the transition to steep size growth at log(M/Msun)~10-10.5, is potentially evidence for a distinct transition between mass-driven quenching and other mechanisms, such as environmentally-driven quenching. Alternatively, this change in the slope of the quiescent size-mass relation could indicate a shift from size growth due to star formation to size growth via mergers or a fundamental limitation on the allowed density of galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Measuring Star-Formation Histories at z~2 with a Semi-Resolved Approach</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/measuring-star-formation-histories-at-z~2-with-a-semi-resolved-approach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/measuring-star-formation-histories-at-z~2-with-a-semi-resolved-approach/</guid><description>&lt;p>Understanding the history of star formation in galaxies is key to gaining a more comprehensive picture of galaxy formation, evolution, and quenching. However, a significant amount of photometric and/or spectroscopic data is necessary to robustly model the non-parametric star-formation histories (SFHs) of galaxies. Semi-resolved SFHs also require the photometry and spectroscopy to be spatially resolved, which limits the use of longer-wavelength data. We present a study of the semi-resolved, 2-component SFHs of 60 z~2 main-sequence, star-forming galaxies in the GOODS-N field, modeled using the Prospector code with a novel iterative method to incorporate unresolved K-band/IRAC data. Our results suggest that selecting star-forming galaxies at cosmic noon may frequently include systems in an “evolved” evolutionary phase where the centers have recently started a burst of star-formation activity that will likely initiate inside-out quenching in the next several hundred million years. Due to the extensive data sets required to model resolved SFHs, we also develop a model to match observed F814W-F160W color gradients from 3D-DASH and COSMOS/ACS imaging to quenching and formation timescales of quenched galaxies at z~2. These timescales provide an overview of the galaxies’ formation time (early or late) and quenching speed (fast or slow), suggesting that the overall evolutionary history of these quenched galaxies at this epoch can be inferred using semi-revolved color gradients.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Differential Assembly of the Centers and Outskirts of Main Sequence Galaxies at z~2.3</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/the-differential-assembly-of-the-centers-and-outskirts-of-main-sequence-galaxies-at-z~2.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/the-differential-assembly-of-the-centers-and-outskirts-of-main-sequence-galaxies-at-z~2.3/</guid><description>&lt;p>We present a sample of 60 z~2.3 main sequence, star-forming galaxies from the MOSDEF survey in GOODS-N with SED fits to decomposed central and outer components. These galaxies are decomposed into two components using apertures selected from observed z-H colors. SED fitting is done with Prospector on HST ACS and WFC3, &lt;em>Spitzer&lt;/em>/IRAC, and ground-based photometry, with additional constraints from MOSDEF metallicities and spectroscopic redshifts. Because we decompose the galaxies into only two components, we are able to iteratively determine the IRAC and ground-based photometry of each component while conserving total flux. Our final sample contains stellar population parameters and SFHs for the center, outskirts, and integrated light of each galaxy. SFHs indicate that the majority of galaxies with logM&amp;lt;10.5 form their central region in bursts of star formation. Moreover, the galaxies with the sharpest peaks in SFR span a wide range in size and central density. This implies that the formation of these central parts likely occurred via an increase in the accretion rate of star forming clumps, rather than the collapse of a gaseous disk. Further analysis of the uncertainties from the decomposition and choice of priors is necessary to determine if these results are robust.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diagnosing DASH: A Morphological Catalog for the COSMOS-DASH Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/diagnosing-dash-a-morphological-catalog-for-the-cosmos-dash-survey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/talk/diagnosing-dash-a-morphological-catalog-for-the-cosmos-dash-survey/</guid><description>&lt;p>COSMOS-DASH is a 0.5 square degree survey of the COSMOS field, obtained utilizing the novel “Drift And SHift” (DASH) observing technique for HST-WFC3 imaging. While DASH observations are significantly more efficient than standard HST imaging, they also are shallower and have an unusual data reduction, both of which may impact morphology measurements for fainter galaxies. In this talk I will present the F160W morphological catalog for for 51,534 galaxies in the COSMOS-DASH survey. Using morphological measurements from GALFIT, we recover consistent results with those from the deeper 3D-HST morphological catalogs out to z=2 and logM~10. I will also discuss the parameter space where morphological fits of DASH galaxies are robustly recovered. At logM&amp;lt;10.5, we find a flattening of the quiescent size-mass relation, implying the sizes of low mass quiescent galaxies are more similar to star-forming galaxies with a similar redshift and mass. Trends with axis-ratio and environment also suggest that low mass galaxies that quench in low density environments may retain morphologies comparable to similar mass star-forming galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>