<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Galaxy Evolution | Sam E. Cutler</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/tag/galaxy-evolution/</link><atom:link href="https://samecutler.github.io/tag/galaxy-evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Galaxy Evolution</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024 Sam Cutler</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://samecutler.github.io/media/icon_hue11b335ae175fd4abb2262113e3113ef_438264_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Galaxy Evolution</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/tag/galaxy-evolution/</link></image><item><title>The UNCOVER Survey: A First-look HST+JWST Catalog of Galaxy Redshifts and Stellar Population Properties Spanning 0.2 ensuremathłesssim z ensuremathłesssim 15</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/wang-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/wang-2024/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Two Distinct Classes of Quiescent Galaxies at Cosmic Noon Revealed by JWST PRIMER and UNCOVER</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/jwstsizes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/jwstsizes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rapid Quenching of Galaxies at Cosmic Noon</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/park-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/park-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Measuring Star-Formation Histories at z 2 with a Semi-Resolved Approach</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/cutler-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/cutler-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Differential Assembly History of the Centers and Outskirts of Main Sequence Galaxies at $z∼2.3$</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/insideout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/insideout/</guid><description/></item><item><title>3D-DASH: The Widest Near-infrared Hubble Space Telescope Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/mowla-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/mowla-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Diagnosing DASH: A Catalog of Structural Properties for the COSMOS-DASH Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/dash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/dash/</guid><description/></item><item><title>COSMOS-DASH</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/cosmos-dash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:51:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/cosmos-dash/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hubble Space Telescope (HST) resolution is crucial in measuring the structural properties of high-redshift or blended galaxies. However, large area surveys are traditionally observationally expensive to obtain with HST, especially in the near-infrared. The COSMOS-DASH survey utilizes the novel &amp;ldquo;Drift And SHift&amp;rdquo; (DASH) technique to efficiently observe up to eight pointings in a single orbit using HST. This is done by guiding with gyros alone (i.e. diabling fine guidance sensors after the first pointing), which allows for wide-area surveys in the NIR with HST resolution, including the 0.49 square degree COSMOS-DASH survey. I lead the creation of the COSMOS-DASH morphological catalog, which provides structural parameters for over 50,000 galaxies with an increased number of massive galaxies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The COSMOS-DASH mosaics and morphological catalog, along with a more detailed description of the program are available on the &lt;a href="https://archive.stsci.edu/hlsp/cosmos-dash" target="_blank" rel="noopener">COSMOS-DASH MAST page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resolved SED fitting with Prospector</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/resolved-prospector/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:51:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/resolved-prospector/</guid><description>&lt;p>The formation of the central parts of &amp;ldquo;typical&amp;rdquo; star-forming galaxies is an open question in astronomy. To investigate this, we present a sample of 60 z~2.3 main-sequence galaxies from the &lt;a href="http://mosdef.astro.berkeley.edu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MOSFIRE Deep Evolution Field (MOSDEF)&lt;/a> spectroscopic survey. Using the &lt;a href="https://prospect.readthedocs.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prospector code&lt;/a> with strong metallicity priors from MOSDEF spectra, we fit SEDs to resolved central and outer components, using a novel iterative method to robustly incorporate unresolved &lt;em>Spitzer&lt;/em>/IRAC and &lt;em>K&lt;/em>-band data. This technique allows us to get well-constrained, non-parametric star formation histories for the central and outer regions of these typical main-sequence galaxies (see the figure above), which provides insight into the overall assembly of star-forming galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Quiescent Galaxy Sizes with JWST</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/jwst-sizes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/jwst-sizes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Several previous HST-based studies (including &lt;a href="https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2022ApJ...925...34C/abstract" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cutler et al. 2022&lt;/a>) have found a flattening of sizes at the low-mass end of the quiescent size-mass relation. Using the improved sensitivity and spatial resolution, and redder wavelength coverage of JWST/NIRCam, we investigate the sizes of low-mass quiescent galaxies in the &lt;a href="https://primer-jwst.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PRIMER&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://jwst-uncover.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UNCOVER&lt;/a> Treasury surveys at cosmic noon (1&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;3). A sample of 332 7&amp;lt;logM&amp;lt;11 galaxies are selected using &lt;em>UVJ&lt;/em> and sSFR criteria and modeled in both F150W and F444W using (&lt;em>GALFIT&lt;/em>)[https://users.obs.carnegiescience.edu/peng/work/galfit/galfit.html]. With these measurements, we find the properties of low-mass quiescent galaxies differ dramatically from their massive counterparts and are better classified as an entirely separate population.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>