<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SED Fitting | Sam E. Cutler</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/tag/sed-fitting/</link><atom:link href="https://samecutler.github.io/tag/sed-fitting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>SED Fitting</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Sam Cutler</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://samecutler.github.io/media/icon_hue11b335ae175fd4abb2262113e3113ef_438264_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>SED Fitting</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/tag/sed-fitting/</link></image><item><title>The Differential Assembly History of the Centers and Outskirts of Main Sequence Galaxies at $z∼2.3$</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/insideout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/insideout/</guid><description>&lt;p>We present a study of spatially-resolved star formation histories (SFHs) for 60 z~2.3 main-sequence, star-forming galaxies selected from the MOSDEF spectroscopic survey in the GOODS-N field, with a median logM=9.75 and a range of 8.6&amp;lt;logM&amp;lt;11.5. Photometry is decomposed into a central and outer spatial component using observed z_F850LP-H_F160W colors. The Prospector code is used to model spectral energy distributions for the centers, outskirts, and integrated galaxy using HST/ACS and WFC3, Spitzer/IRAC, and ground-based photometry, with additional constraints on gas-phase metallicity and spectroscopic redshift from MOSDEF spectroscopy. For the low-resolution bands, spatially-resolved photometry is determined with an iterative approach. The reconstructed SFHs indicate that the majority of galaxies with logM&amp;lt;10.5 are observed while their central regions undergo relatively recent (&amp;lt;100 Myr) bursts of star formation, while the outskirts have a smooth, quasi-steady SFH. The enhanced star formation activity of the central parts is broadly consistent with the idea that it is produced by highly dissipative gas compaction and accretion. The wide range of central densities and sizes observed in the sample suggests that for the selected galaxies this process has started but is still far from being completed. The implication would be that selecting star-forming galaxies at cosmic noon frequently includes systems in an &amp;ldquo;evolved&amp;rdquo; evolutionary phase where the centers have recently started a burst of star formation activity that will likely initiate inside-out quenching in the next several hundred million years.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Resolved SED fitting with Prospector</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/project/resolved-prospector/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:51:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/project/resolved-prospector/</guid><description>&lt;p>The formation of the central parts of &amp;ldquo;typical&amp;rdquo; star-forming galaxies is an open question in astronomy. To investigate this, we present a sample of 60 z~2.3 main-sequence galaxies from the &lt;a href="http://mosdef.astro.berkeley.edu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MOSFIRE Deep Evolution Field (MOSDEF)&lt;/a> spectroscopic survey. Using the &lt;a href="https://prospect.readthedocs.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prospector code&lt;/a> with strong metallicity priors from MOSDEF spectra, we fit SEDs to resolved central and outer components, using a novel iterative method to robustly incorporate unresolved &lt;em>Spitzer&lt;/em>/IRAC and &lt;em>K&lt;/em>-band data. This technique allows us to get well-constrained, non-parametric star formation histories for the central and outer regions of these typical main-sequence galaxies (see the figure above), which provides insight into the overall assembly of star-forming galaxies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>