<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications | Sam E. Cutler</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/</link><atom:link href="https://samecutler.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Publications</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Sam Cutler</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://samecutler.github.io/media/icon_hue11b335ae175fd4abb2262113e3113ef_438264_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Publications</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/</link></image><item><title>Rapid Quenching of Galaxies at Cosmic Noon</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2022-ar-xiv-221003747-p/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2022-ar-xiv-221003747-p/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Differential Assembly History of the Centers and Outskirts of Main Sequence Galaxies at $z∼2.3$</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2022-ar-xiv-220801653-c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2022-ar-xiv-220801653-c/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Differential Assembly History of the Centers and Outskirts of Main Sequence Galaxies at $z∼2.3$</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/insideout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/insideout/</guid><description>&lt;p>We present a study of spatially-resolved star formation histories (SFHs) for 60 z~2.3 main-sequence, star-forming galaxies selected from the MOSDEF spectroscopic survey in the GOODS-N field, with a median logM=9.75 and a range of 8.6&amp;lt;logM&amp;lt;11.5. Photometry is decomposed into a central and outer spatial component using observed z_F850LP-H_F160W colors. The Prospector code is used to model spectral energy distributions for the centers, outskirts, and integrated galaxy using HST/ACS and WFC3, Spitzer/IRAC, and ground-based photometry, with additional constraints on gas-phase metallicity and spectroscopic redshift from MOSDEF spectroscopy. For the low-resolution bands, spatially-resolved photometry is determined with an iterative approach. The reconstructed SFHs indicate that the majority of galaxies with logM&amp;lt;10.5 are observed while their central regions undergo relatively recent (&amp;lt;100 Myr) bursts of star formation, while the outskirts have a smooth, quasi-steady SFH. The enhanced star formation activity of the central parts is broadly consistent with the idea that it is produced by highly dissipative gas compaction and accretion. The wide range of central densities and sizes observed in the sample suggests that for the selected galaxies this process has started but is still far from being completed. The implication would be that selecting star-forming galaxies at cosmic noon frequently includes systems in an &amp;ldquo;evolved&amp;rdquo; evolutionary phase where the centers have recently started a burst of star formation activity that will likely initiate inside-out quenching in the next several hundred million years.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>3D-DASH: The Widest Near-infrared Hubble Space Telescope Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2022-ap-j-933-129-m/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2022-ap-j-933-129-m/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Diagnosing DASH: A Catalog of Structural Properties for the COSMOS-DASH Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2022-ap-j-925-34-c/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2022-ap-j-925-34-c/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Diagnosing DASH: A Catalog of Structural Properties for the COSMOS-DASH Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/dash/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/dash/</guid><description>&lt;p>We present the F160W morphological catalogs for the COSMOS-DASH survey, the largest area near-IR survey using HST-WFC3 to date. Utilizing the &amp;ldquo;Drift And SHift&amp;rdquo; observing technique for HST-WFC3 imaging, the COSMOS-DASH survey imaged approximately 0.5 square degrees of the UltraVISTA deep stripes (0.7 sq. deg. when combined with archival data). Global structural parameters are measured for 51,586 galaxies within COSMOS-DASH using GALFIT (excluding the CANDELS area) with detection using a deep multi-band HST image. We recover consistent results with those from the deeper 3D-HST morphological catalogs, finding that, in general, sizes and Sérsic indices of typical galaxies are accurate to limiting magnitudes of H&amp;lt;23 and H&amp;lt;22 ABmag, respectively. In size-mass parameter space, galaxies in COSMOS-DASH demonstrate robust morphological measurements out to z~2 and down to logM~9. With the advantage of the larger area of COSMOS-DASH, we measure a flattening of the quiescent size-mass relation below logM~10.5 that persists out to z~2. We show that environment is not the primary driver of this flattening, at least out to z=1.2, whereas internal physical processes may instead govern the structural evolution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diagnosing DASH: A Morphological Catalog for the COSMOS-DASH Survey</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2021-aas-23734211-c/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2021-aas-23734211-c/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Examining High Redshift Rotation Curves and Dark Matter Profiles Outside the Local Universe</title><link>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2018-aas-23135603-c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samecutler.github.io/publication/2018-aas-23135603-c/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>